cosdna.com 2019-12-20

# Privacy Policy | CosDNA

##### Who is collecting the data

Protecting your private information is our priority. This Statement of Privacy applies to cosdna.com and governs data collection and usage. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to CosDNA. including cosdna.com and CosDNA. By using the CosDNA website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

##### What data is being collected

In order to better provide you with products and services offered on our Site, CosDNA may collect personally identifiable information, such as your:  
. User Account (Alias you choice)  
. E-Mail Address  
. Birth Year  

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through CosDNA’s public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others.

We do not collect any personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us. However, you may be required to provide certain personal information to us when you elect to use certain products or services available on the Site. These may include: (a) registering for an account on our Site; (b) signing up for special offers from selected third parties; (c) sending us an email message. To wit, we will use your information for, but not limited to, communicating with you in relation to services and/or products you have requested from us. We also may gather additional personal or non-personal information in the future.

##### Use of your Personal Information

CosDNA collects and uses your personal information to operate its website(s) and deliver the services you have requested.

CosDNA may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from CosDNA and its affiliates.

##### Sharing Information with Third Parties

CosDNA does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties.

CosDNA may disclose your personal information, without notice, if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on CosDNA or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of CosDNA; and/or (c) act under the exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of CosDNA, or the public.

##### Tracking User Behavior

CosDNA may keep track of the websites and pages our users visit within CosDNA, in order to determine what CosDNA services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within CosDNA to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area. 

##### Automatically Collected Information

Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by CosDNA. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the CosDNA website.

##### Use of Cookies

The CosDNA website may use “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize CosDNA pages, or register with CosDNA site or services, a cookie helps CosDNA to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, visit history, and so on. When you return to the same CosDNA website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the CosDNA features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept of decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the CosDNA services or websites you visit.

##### How We Respond to Do Not Track Signals

Some internet browsers have incorporated "Do Not Track" features. Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference (the "DNT Signal") to the web sites you visit indicating that you do not wish to be tracked. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret DNT Signals, nor a common definition of "tracking", we do not currently respond to DNT Signals on the CosDNA Websites. CosDNA engages in so-called online behavioral advertising on third-party sites (also sometimes called "retargeting" or “tracking”), through which information collected about the pages you visit on CosDNA is used to display ads for CosDNA products or services on third-party websites. This information may uniquely identify a browser but is not personally identifiable.

##### Online Behavioral Advertising

CosDNA may use third-party online advertising companies to provide you with CosDNA advertisements that may be relevant to your interests, as determined by your activity on CosDNA and non-CosDNA websites. This type of ad customization is known as "online behavioral” or “interest-based” advertising. These advertising companies may use cookies to understand your interests based on, for example, pages visited and browsing patterns on CosDNA and non-CosDNA websites.

##### Opting Out of Online Behavioral Advertising

You may opt-out of receiving online behavioral advertisements from third-party advertising companies that CosDNA uses to serve these interest-based ads. Because CosDNA participates in the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) self-regulatory program, we have adopted the use of the DAA’s Advertising Options Icon (AdChoices) on these ads for the purpose of allowing users the ability to opt-out of this form of tracking. You may click on the AdChoices icon to opt out of receiving behaviorally-targeted ads that are served to you based on your browsing behavior on CosDNA websites. Please note that opting out through the AdChoices icon will only affect ads served to you based on your behavior on CosDNA websites, and does not prevent you from receiving other CosDNA advertising. You may also opt out of receiving behaviorally-targeted ads directly at our website using this link: AdChoices. Opting out through the CosDNA website, as opposed to using the AdChoices icon, means the data about your behaviors on CosDNA websites won’t be used by third party advertising companies to serve you interest-based ads. 

The methods of both collecting data for the purpose of serving behaviorally-targeted ads and recording your opt-out are done at the individual computer browser level and are based on browser cookies. If you clear your cookies or use a different browser or computer, you will need to re-submit your preference to the specified third-party advertising companies. For more information about behavioral advertising, please visit http://www.aboutads.info.

Furthermore, we may allow third-parties, including Google, to serve you ads on CosDNA and to store cookies for future use. Although we do not provide such third-parties with information that can identify your personally, this use of cookies, including Google’s use of the DART cookie, still enables them and their partners to serve you ads based on your visits to CosDNA and/or other sites on the Internet. We do not control whether third-parties respond to "do not track" signals, but you may opt out of the use of advertising cookies, including the DART cookie, by [visiting](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads) the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page. 

##### Links

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

##### E-mail Communication

From time to time, CosDNA may contact you via email for the purpose of providing announcements, promotional offers, alerts, confirmations, surveys, and/or other general communication. In order to improve our Services, we may receive a notification when you open an email from CosDNA or click on a link therin.

If you would like to stop receiving marketing or promotional communications via email from CosDNA, you may managing your notification preferences in your Account Settings.

##### External Data Storage Sites

We may store your data on servers provided by third-party hosting vendors with whom we have contracted.

##### Changes to this Statement

CosDNA reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your account, by placing a prominent notice on our site, and/or by updating any privacy information on this page. Your continued use of the Site and/or Services available through this Site after such modifications will constitute your: (a) acknowledgment of the modified Privacy Policy; and (b) agreement to abide and be bound by that Policy.
